Guide to the National Guardian Photographs PHOTOS.213
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
National Guardian Photographs
1948-1992
PHOTOS.213
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
33.0 linear feet in 32 record cartons and 1 oversize flat box
The National Guardian (later known as The Guardian) was a radical leftist weekly newspaper published in New York City between 1948 and 1992. The National Guardian reported on labor, activism, reform, and social movements without particular party affiliations, advocating for a unified leftist party in the United States. Known for its independent and investigative journalism, the paper produced significant pieces on civil rights and the Cold War, and was one of the few publications to print news sympathetic to Julius and Ethel Rosenberg during their trial and execution, with much of the paper's reporting coming from William A. Reuben. This collection is comprised of the photograph files of the National Guardian, consisting of approximately 44,465 8x10 black-and-white photographic prints, along with some original cartoons and other graphic materials. The materials reflect the subject matter of the newspaper itself, reporting labor, activism, reform, and social movements.
National guardian.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Gregory Jocz in 2005. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2005.041 and NPA.2005.122.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Scope and Content Note
This collection is comprised of the photograph files of the National Guardian, consisting of approximately 44,465 8x10 black-and-white photographic prints, along with some original cartoons and other graphic materials. The materials reflect the subject matter of the newspaper itself, reporting on labor and the left without particular party affiliations, advocating for a unified leftist party in the United States. Known for its independent and investigative journalism, the paper produced numerous significant articles concerning civil rights and the Cold War, including coverage of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg's trial and execution. The photographs document both domestic and international events, with an emphasis on activism, reform, and social movements.
Related Archival Materials
Cedric Belfrage Papers (TAM 143)
Sally Belfrage Papers (TAM 189)
Historical/Biographical Note
The National Guardian (later known as The Guardian) was a radical leftist weekly newspaper published in New York City between 1948 and 1992. The paper was founded by James Aronson, Cedric Belfrage, and John T. McManus with the purpose of providing an alternative perspective to the mainstream media during the Cold War. The paper's early years focused on and supported New Deal programs and the New York American Labor Party (ALP). The National Guardian reported on labor, activism, reform, and social movements without particular party affiliations, advocating for a unified leftist party in the United States. Known for its independent and investigative journalism, the paper produced significant pieces on civil rights and the Cold War, and was one of the few publications to print news sympathetic to Julius and Ethel Rosenberg during their trial and execution, with much of the paper's reporting coming from William A. Reuben.
During the 1960s, the paper shifted directions toward the New Left, with Aronson selling his shares and the publication changing its name to the Guardian. In the 1970s, the Guardian supported Marxism-Leninism, calling for a new Marxist-Leninist party in the United States. The paper established Guardian Clubs for readers in the 1980s, which gave rise to competitor publications Frontline and Line of March. After years of declining circulation and financial difficulties, the paper ceased publication in 1992.
Jocz, Gregory; Black-and-white photographs.; Counterculture |z United States |v Newspapers.; New Left |z United States |v Newspapers.; Peace movements |z United States |v Newspapers.; Social movements |z United States |v Newspapers.; United States |x Politics and government |v Newspapers.
- Mozambique, 1984-1992; 2.0 folders (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Mozambique – Aid, 1987-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Mozambique – Children, 1983-1988; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Mozambique – Crime, 1991-; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Mozambique – Culture, 1987-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mozambique – Economy, 1988-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Mozambique – Education, 1987-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mozambique – Environment, 1989-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mozambique – Government, 1989-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mozambique – Famine, 1989-; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mozambique – Farms, 1988-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Mozambique – FRELIMO, 1988-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Mozambique – Health, 1990-; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Mozambique – Housing, 1984-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Mozambique – Infrastructure, 1988-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Mozambique – International Relations, 1987-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Mozambique – Labor, 1987-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Mozambique – Media, 1990-; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Mozambique – Military, 1983-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Mozambique – Opposition, 1991-; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Mozambique – Personalities, 1987-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Mozambique – Refugees, 1987-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Mozambique – Religion, 1988-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Mozambique – RENAMO, 1988-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Mozambique – Sports, 1988-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Mozambique – Transportation, 1989-; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Mozambique – War, 1984-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Mozambique – Women, 1987-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Nambia, 1984-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 32)
- NATO/Warsaw Military, 1989-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Nepal, 1990-; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Nicaragua, 1981-1991; 6.0 folders (Box 1, Folder 35-40)
- N. Korea, 1988-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Pakistan, 1984-1987; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Panama, 1989-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Peru, 1989-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Philippines, 1984-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Poland, 1990-; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Romania, 1989-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 47)
- South Africa, 1985-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 48)
- S. Korea, 1953-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Spain, 1986-1988; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Soviet Union, 1986-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 51)
- U.S./Iraq War, 1990-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Venezuela, 1990-; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Vietnam, 1979-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 54)
- West Bank/Gaza, 1984-1990; 2.0 folders (Box 1, Folder 55-56)
- Yugoslavia, 1987-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Zaire, 1985-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Zimbabwe, 1990-; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 59)
- International Personalities, 1984-1990; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Personalities, 1984-1992; 2.0 folders (Box 1, Folder 61-62)
- M. Harold Washington, 1984-1987; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Jesse Jackson, 1984-1988; 1.0 folder (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Domestic Personalities – General, 1984-1991; 3.0 folders (Box 1, Folder 65-67)
- John Birch Society, 1961-1967; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Minutemen, 1966-1975; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Right-wing groups, misc., 1963-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Demo – Racism, Mar.1975-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Ku Klux Klan, 1960-1966; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Corporate Corruption – Crime, 1961-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Graf, 1955-1964; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Rackets – Crime (Including Mafia, Cosa Nostra), 1963-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Volunteer Law Enforcers, 1968-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Weatherman, 1969-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Police and Equipment, 1960-1970; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Bombings – Sabotage, 1968-1975; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Kent State, etc. Student (College) Protests, 1964-1977; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Peace Summit, 1960-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Peace, 1960-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Transcontinental Walk for Peace, 1961-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Anti-War, 1965-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Washington, D.C. Demonstration for Peace and Against Air Strikes at North Vietnam and Against the War in Vietnam, Apr. 17, 1965-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Peace, 1962-; 2.0 folders (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
- Peace Women Strike for Peace, 1962-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Peace-Geneva Disarmament Conference, 1966-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 22)
- January – Peace – April, Jan. 1966-Apr.1966; 2.0 folders (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
- Anti-War NYC, Mar. 26, 1966-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Peace, Sept. 1966-Dec. 1966; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Hiroshima & Hiroshima Demonstrations Worldwide, 1955-1960; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Parliamentary Union – Interparliamentary Union Conference – Belgrade, Yugoslavia, Sept. 12, 1963-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Bombing, 1964-1974; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Anti-War Demonstrations and Protest, 1961-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Anti-war Demonstrations, 1965-1972; 2.0 folders (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
- Peace, 1961-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Peace, May. 1, 1966-Aug. 1966; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 34)
- War Crimes, 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Stock Market, 1929-1966; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Peace [Empty], 1964-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Peace, Jan. 1967-Mra. 1967; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Demo – War, 1971-1975; 2.0 folders (Box 2, Folder 39-40)
- Peace, 1965-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Peace, 1961-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Peace, 1963-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Peace, Easter, 1961-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Moratorium, 1969-; 1.0 folder (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Peace–International War Crimes Tribunal Stockholm, Sweden, Apr. 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Counter-inauguration, 1969-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Anti-War, 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Peace, Jul. 1967-Sep. 1967; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Peace – Foreign Countries, 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Pentagon– demonstrations and protests, 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Afghanistan, 1960-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Albania, 1981-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Algeria, 1982-1988; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Argentina, 1957-1988; 2.0 folders (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
- Australia, 1952-1988; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Asia & Australia miscellaneous, 1984-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Austria, 1980-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Bahamas Barbados, 1980-1982; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Bangladesh, 1974-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Bangladesh Population Control, 1972-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Belau, 1986-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Belgium, 1982-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Belize, 1975-1994; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Bermuda, 1981-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Bolivia, 1955-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Brazil, miscellaneous, 1955-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Brazil – Personalities, 1982-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Brazil, 1983-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Britain – Peace, 1982-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Britain: Blacks, Poor, 1981-1988; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Britain – miscellaneous, 1982-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Britain – Personalities, 1985-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 30)
- U.K. Miners Britain, 1984-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Bulgaria, 1980-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Burma, 1984-1988; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Caribbean, 1982-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Recent China, 1989-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 35)
- China – Personalities, 1975-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 36)
- China – miscellaneous, 1959-1987; 2.0 folders (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
- China – Tibet, 1989-; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Columbia, 1974-1988; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Costa Rica, 1974-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Cuba, 1970-1987; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Articles, 1987-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Dot Supplies, 1990-1991; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Cuba Demonstrations within & support, 1971-1980; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Military, 1961-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Housing, 1960-1981; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Religion, 1973-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Health, 1983-1987; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Cuba – Personalities, 1984-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Women in Cuba, 1961-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Labor in Cuba (Workers...), 1966-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Cuba (by Nancy), 1959-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Cyprus, 1981-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Czechoslovakia, 1982-1984; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Czechoslovakia [Oversize], 1963-1973; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Denmark, 1982-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Disarmament Int., 1984-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Dominican Republic, 1970-1979; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Dominican Republic, 1978-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Dominican Republic, 1961-1980; 2.0 folders (Box 3, Folder 61-62)
- Dominica, 1965-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 63)
- E. Timor, 1975-1976; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Ecuador, 1979-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Egypt photo, 1986-1987; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Egypt, 1982-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Equat. Guinea, 1982-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 3, Folder 68)
- El Salvador – miscellaneous, 1981-1989; 2.0 folders (Box 3, Folder 69-70)
- El Salvador – guerilla, liberated zones and left in general, 1982-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 1)
- El Salvador (Popular Movement), 1983-1989; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 2)
- El Salvador (Labour), 1985-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 3)
- El Salvador by Kufeld, 1985-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 4)
- El Salvador armed forces (militia, army, civil guard), 1966-1984; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 5)
- VVAW, 1969-1973; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Native American Culture, 1949-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Native American Personalities, 1974-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Indians Sit-in, 1970-1978; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 9)
- U.S. Imperialism Graphics, 1973-1976; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Hippies, 1967-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Hippies, 1967-1970; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 12)
- S.D.S., 1966-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Arab-Israeli Relations, 1969-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Anti-War D.C., Nov. 13, 1969-Nov. 15, 1969; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Anti-War, 1968-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Anti-War, 1969-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Democratic Convention, 1968-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Misc. Demonstrations U.S., 1969-1983; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Young Lords, 1970-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Young Lords Party, 1965-1975; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Anti-War/Disarmament, 1978-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Ban-the-Bomb, 1960-1962; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 23)
- International Industrialists Conference, 1966-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Anti-Dow, 1969-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 25)
- International Demons, 1979-1980; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Anti-Nazi, 1960-1966; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Prepositions 13, 1978-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Disabled, undated; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Miscellaneous U.S. Graphics, 1976-1979; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Foreign Policy, 1969-1975; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Health Care, 1966-1978; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Stop the Draft Week, 1968-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Newark, NJ – Ghetto Rebellions, 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Wallace – For & Against, 1968-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Anti-War, 1966-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Peace – Anti-War Demonstrations, 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Hard Times Conference –Chicago, Feb. 1975-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Kent State, 1970-1980; 2.0 folders (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
- Student Demonstrations & Anti-War, 1970-1979; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Student Demonstrations, 1970-1979; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Student (College) Protests, 1960-1969; 3.0 folders (Box 4, Folder 43-45)
- May Day Actions, 1973-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 46)
- May Day International (Industry & Labor), 1923-1960; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 47)
- School Budget Cutbacks, 1976-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Elijah Muhammad Leader of the Black Muslims, 1964-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Nov. 4 Coalition, 1972-1973; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Left-Wing Religious, 1956-1972; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Miscellaneous Groups, 1967-1975; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 52)
- VIPs – U.S., 1972-1978; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Nukes, 1979-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 54)
- America First, 1941-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 55)
- American National Party-Organizations & Groups, 1961-1962; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Asian-Americans, 1969-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Alianza Federal de Pueblos Libres, 1967-1968; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 58)
- DuBois Club, 1966-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Left-Wing Groups Miscellaneous, 1959-1965; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Moral Re-Armament Assembly, 1957-1961; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 61)
- National Conference on New Politics, 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 62)
- National Student Association, 1967-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 63)
- Peace & Freedom Party [Empty?], undated; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Student National Coordinating Committee Formerly Student National Coordinating Committee, 1966-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Vietnam Day Committee, 1966-; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 66)
- CP, 1920-1966; 1.0 folder (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Communist Part, 1941-1966; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Viet Vets (for Peace), 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Young Americans for Freedom, 1962-1966; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Job Discrimination, 1960-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 4)
- American Nazi Party, 1961-1967; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Yippies & Crazies Youth International Party, 1968-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Evictions and Squatters, 1954-1957; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Interracial Marriage, 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Peace – Fort Hood GIs, 1966-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Demo before 70 War, 1967-1975; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 10)
- [Oversized] Mine Workers, 1973-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Watts Riot, LA –Civil Rights, 1965-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Ohio, 1965-1966; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Riots, 1965-1982; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Black Struggle, 1970-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 15)
- BAKKE Black Struggle, 1978-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Atlanta Murderers – Williams, 1981-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Black Struggle, 1971-1974; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Black Struggle, 1975-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Black Struggle, 1976-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Black Struggle, 1977-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Wilmington V Ben Chavis Ten, 1977-1978; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Blacks & Other Minorities, 1964-1980; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Racism, 1976-1978; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Black Struggle, 1979-1986; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Wiley, 1970-1980; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Civil Liberties – Rights Mack Charies Parker – Lynching, 1959-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Georgia – Ghetto Rebellions, 1967-1974; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Blacks in Sports, 1949-1961; 2.0 folders (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
- Angela Davis – Ruchell Magee Trial, Soledad Brothers, 1970-1972; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Women’s Issues, 1978-1979; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Ku Klux Klan and other Racist Groups, 1960-1980; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Women—Jobs & Personalities, 1956-1984; 2.0 folders (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
- Women, 1977-1984; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Abortion, 1977-1989; 2.0 folders (Box 5, Folder 37-38)
- Women Demonstrations, 1989-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Women, 1984-1989; 2.0 folders (Box 5, Folder 40-41)
- Roe V. Wade Demo-Union Square, Jan. 1988-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Anti-Poverty Programs, 1960-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Demonstrations Women, 1986-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Civil Rights Demonstrations, 1962-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Black Struggle, 1968-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Poor Peoples March– Civil Rights, 1968-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Black Struggle, 1967-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Black Struggle, 1969-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Black Struggle, 1954-1956; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Black Struggle, 1964-; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 51)
- James Meredith—Black Struggle, 1962-1963; 1.0 folder (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Freedom Democratic Party Mississippi, 1965-; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Alabama– Civil Rights, 1965-; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Women Demonstrations 1988, 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 3)
- The U.S. Weapons in South Vietnam, 1966-1975; 2.0 folders (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
- The U.S. Air Bases in South Vietnam, 1966-1975; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
- During the Liberation of South Vietnam, 1966-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 7)
- The Celebration of Armed Forces After the Liberation of South Vietnam, 1975-1976; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 8)
- The G.I. in Action Before the Vietnamese Liberation, 1966-1972; 2.0 folders (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
- The U.S. Marine Bases, 1965-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 11)
- South Vietnam People and Student Demonstrations, 1963-1976; 2.0 folders (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
- Foreign Demonstrations Against Vietnam War, 1966-1972; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 14)
- South Vietnamese Monks’ Demonstration, 1966-1985; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Politics of South Vietnam During U.S. War, 1965-1974; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 16)
- The U.S. War of Destruction and Defoliation in South Vietnam Area, 1965-1974; 2.0 folders (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
- Vietnamese Prisoner in South Vietnam During the U.S. War, 1967-1973; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 19)
- The Victims of U.S. Crimes in South Vietnam, 1966-1969; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Daily Ways of Life of the People in South Vietnam Before the Liberation, 1966-1975; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Daily Ways of Life of the People in South Vietnam Before the Liberation, 1964-1978; 2.0 folders (Box 6, Folder 22-23)
- The Soldier’s Way of Life After Fighting in South Vietnam, 1953-1975; 2.0 folders (Box 6, Folder 24-25)
- Children in South Vietnam During U.S. War, 1966-1985; 2.0 folders (Box 6, Folder 26-27)
- Daily Ways of Life of the People in South Vietnam Before the Liberation, 1966-1985; 2.0 folders (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
- Vietnam/Cambodia/Laos, 1965-1976; 1.0 folder (Box 6, Folder 30)
- The G.I. in Action Before the Vietnamese Liberation, 1963-1972; 2.0 folders (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- Vietnamese Refugees During U.S. War, 1967-1978; 1.0 folder (Box 7, Folder 3)
- The G.I. in Action Before the Vietnamese Liberation, 1966-1984; 2.0 folders (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
- Anti-Apartheid, 1984-1987; 1.0 folder (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Anti-War, Black Panther, Protests, 1957-1971; 1.0 folder (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Disarmament Actions, 1983-; 1.0 folder (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Demonstrations – Anti-Draft, 1979-1984; 1.0 folder (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Demo – Bork, 1987-; 1.0 folder (Box 7, Folder 10)